<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshops on Sara Soueidan</title>
    <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workshops on Sara Soueidan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Front-End Espresso Shot Workshop by Sara Soueidan</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/front-end-espresso-shot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/front-end-espresso-shot/</guid>
      <description>CSS has seen a lot of new feature releases in the last few years. Keeping up with everything can sometimes be overwhelming. It’s even harder for many designers and developers to ditch the tools and frameworks they’re already familiar with and relying on, in favor of new, native “frameworks” with a less than familiar syntax. But doing so is the way forward. CSS’s native features like Flexbox and Grid as well as CSS Variables provide a lot more power and flexibility than any previous frameworks or tools did—power than we should embrace and put to good use today moving forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SVG Coffee Cup Workshop by Sara Soueidan</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/svg-coffee-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/svg-coffee-cup/</guid>
      <description>Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) are one of the most powerful tools in our front-end development arsenal. Using SVG, you can create accessible, semantic images, icons, and animated documents. But because of the nature of SVG as both an image format and a document format, it can sometimes be overwhelming because there are so many ways to do things that it can be hard to decide which to use when.  Though not new—SVG is more than 15 years old—browser support is still not optimal, and so SVG might—at first glance—seem not worth the trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>