<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Sara Soueidan</title>
    <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/tags/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Sara Soueidan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sarasoueidan.com/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer of the Year 2015 net Award</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/2015/09/22/developer-of-the-year-2-15-net-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/2015/09/22/developer-of-the-year-2-15-net-award/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday, I gave my first keynote in the UK at Generate Conf. That same day, the net awards were announced. On Saturday, I came back home with an award: the Developer of the Year award. This is a short thank you post to everyone involved.   Photo by net magazine. All rights reserved. (Original Photo)   A few months ago, many fellow designers and developers nominated me for two net awards: Outstanding Contribution and Developer of the Year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4, Smashing Book 5</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/2015/07/21/smashing-book-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/2015/07/21/smashing-book-5/</guid>
      <description>The new Smashing Book is out! It’s packed with a lot of time-saving, practical techniques for crafting fast, maintainable and scalable responsive websites. I wrote a chapter in the book—Chapter 4: Mastering SVG For Responsive Web Design. Here is an overview of what that chapter covers, and why I think you should buy the book. Photo credit: Mattia Compagnucci  I always get questions from my followers about a good place to start learning SVG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Won A Web Platform Award</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/2015/04/22/oreilly-web-platform-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/2015/04/22/oreilly-web-platform-award/</guid>
      <description>Today, O&amp;rsquo;Reilly&amp;rsquo;s Fluent Conf is taking place in San Francisco, California. And as part of the conference, the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Web Platform Awards were announced. Apparently, I was nominated for an award and, according to the co-chairs of the conference, I got the most amount of nominations and eventually won an award.
   O’Reilly Web Platform Awards recognize individual contributors who have demonstrated exceptional leadership, creativity, and collaboration in the development of JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and the supporting Web ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Wrote A CSS &lt;del&gt;Book&lt;/del&gt; Reference.</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/2015/02/04/codrops-css-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/2015/02/04/codrops-css-reference/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, we finally released a long-awaited project over at Codrops: Codrops&#39; new CSS Reference, authored by yours truly. Even though I wrote a post over at Codrops introducing the reference and its features, I want to share a little bit more about my experience writing it.
Please note that as of January 2016, I am no longer the maintainer of the Codrops CSS Reference. Thus, unlike my usual highly-technical blog posts, this is a (possibly-boring, but short!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>