<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sara Soueidan</title>
    <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sara Soueidan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sarasoueidan.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hire Me</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/hire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/hire/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m currently considering new projects for Summer–Fall 2017.      There is something magical when you work with somebody knowledgeable, passionate, smart and extremely reliable. When working with Sara, that’s exactly the feeling you get — Sara is very professional with a keen eye for detail, knowing how to work around pitfalls and working hard to get to the best possible solution every single time.   Vitaly Friedman</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Client Work If you are a potential client and want to inquire about front-end development work, please refer to the Hire Me page for more details, or send me an email now. You’ll hear back from me within 2–4 days.  Speaking Requests  To inquire about having me speak at your event, please see the Speaking &amp;amp; Podcasts page. I’ve prepared everything you need to know before and when you invite me to speak to your event in that page, including a press kit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking &amp; Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/speaking/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Talks Past Appearances Podcasts Request A Talk Press Kit    Due to low capacity, I am not currently accepting more speaking engagements for 2017. I’ve got a few unannounced ones, in addition to the ones listed below, that I hope I will be adding to this list soon. Got plans for 2018? Get in touch! Talk + Workshop
13–14 June, 2017 New York City, USA
SmashingConf   Watch Video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a fully-accessible help tooltip</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/accessible-tooltips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/accessible-tooltips/</guid>
      <description>Today is one of those days that started out with a Google search for yet another accessibility question/concern. I’m working on a new project for my client Provata and part of that project is to build a sweet and seemingly simple help tooltip which explains to the reader/user what the Framingham calculator is. The tooltip is triggered by a small help icon like the one shown in the top right corner of this screenshot:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Tips for Getting More Work Done While Traveling</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/knomo-travel-productivity-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/knomo-travel-productivity-tips/</guid>
      <description>Staying productive during traveling can sometimes be a challenge. There are some things you can do to make the most out of your transit times and get more work done. Knomo—a UK based company that makes bags for digital nomads and techies like us, asked me to share some tips for staying productive while traveling. I shared four of the most important ones. I hope you find them useful! I will be sharing many more in another blog post too, so stay tuned!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mimic Relative Positioning Inside an SVG with Nested SVGs</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/mimic-relative-positioning-in-svg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/mimic-relative-positioning-in-svg/</guid>
      <description>Positioning elements inside an SVG image is very similar—if not identical—to positioning elements absolutely in HTML. Every element in SVG is positioned &#34;absolutely&#34; relative to the SVG viewport, and the position inside the viewport is governed by the current coordinate system in use. But this similarity in positioning elements should not conceal the fact that there is a fundamental difference between SVG elements and HTML elements: SVG elements do not have a box model like HTML elements do in CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making the Switch Away from Icon Fonts to SVG: Converting Font Icons to SVG</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/icon-fonts-to-svg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/icon-fonts-to-svg/</guid>
      <description>If you’re reading this article, then I can probably assume you’ve already decided to switch from using fonts for icons to an SVG icon system. Or maybe you&#39;re pondering the idea and want to get an overview of how that would be done and whether or not it&#39;s worth it. Either way, this post is here to help you with that. If you&amp;rsquo;re not already convinced as to why SVG is a better icon system, then I highly recommend reading this article—a cagematch-style comparison between icon fonts and inline SVG for icon systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SVG Style Inheritance and the ‘Flash Of Unstyled SVG’</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-style-inheritance-and-FOUSVG/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-style-inheritance-and-FOUSVG/</guid>
      <description>There are too few things not to like about SVG, and I don’t mean the things that browsers cause by incomplete or lack of certain features or buggy implementations. Yet you might sometimes get some unpredictable results that might frustrate you when working with SVG, if you don’t know the details of how certain features should behave and what to expect from them, as per the specifications. SVG presentation attributes come with a bit of their own behavior which might sometimes surprise you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 In Review</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/2015-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/2015-in-review/</guid>
      <description>Happy new year! 🌟
OK, I felt awkward starting a blog post that way—I confess. ☺️ But this is also an unusual post—not an article about CSS or SVG, and not a lengthy tutorial about web development. It is also the quickest post I ever wrote.
This is my first time writing a year in review kind of post. A lot of great stuff has happened in 2015 that I thought are worth documenting and have a look back at a few years from now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated SVG vs GIF [CAGEMATCH]</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-vs-gif/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-vs-gif/</guid>
      <description>SVG can do much more than display static images. Its animation capabilities are one of its most powerful features, giving it a distinctive advantage over all other image formats. They are one of many reasons that make SVG images better than raster images, including GIFs. But this, of course, only applies to images that are good candidates for SVG, such as:
 Logos, non-complex, vector-based illustrations, user interface controls,  infographics, and icons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Creating and Exporting Better SVGs for the Web</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-tips-for-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-tips-for-designers/</guid>
      <description>Working with SVG in a RWD workflow usually involves a design phase and a development phase. The design phase is usually handled by designers who may or may not know how to code. And because of the nature of SVG as both an image format and a document format, every step taken in the graphics editor in the process of creating the SVG directly affects the resulting code and hence the work of the developer in charge of embedding, scripting or animating the SVG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer of the Year 2015 net Award</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/developer-of-the-year-2-15-net-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/developer-of-the-year-2-15-net-award/</guid>
      <description>Last Friday, I gave my first keynote in the UK at Generate Conf. That same day, the net awards were announced. On Saturday, I came back home with an award: the Developer of the Year award. This is a short thank you post to everyone involved.   Photo by net magazine. All rights reserved. (Original Photo)   A few months ago, many fellow designers and developers nominated me for two net awards: Outstanding Contribution and Developer of the Year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS vs. SVG: The Final Round(up)</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-vs-svg-the-final-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-vs-svg-the-final-roundup/</guid>
      <description>This is the last article in the series of article comparing common CSS techniques to their SVG counterparts. This article is a roundup of several CSS and SVG solutions, as opposed to being an article comparing one solution that can be achieved using either CSS and SVG. There are already a bunch of excellent articles out there that cover the details for each of these solutions, so we will get an overview of each solution and link to those articles for each section as we go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS vs. SVG: Shapes and Arbitrarily-Shaped UI Components</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-vs-svg-arbitrarily-shaped-ui-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-vs-svg-arbitrarily-shaped-ui-components/</guid>
      <description>This post is the third in the series of posts exploring techniques and examples that can be achieved using both CSS and SVG, and compares them both.In this article, we are going to go over techniques for creating arbitrarily-shaped UI components using CSS properties and SVG’s capabilities, and a mix of both! Specifically, we will be talking about how to create circular menus, as these are the perfect example of usable non-rectangular UI elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS vs SVG: Styling Checkboxes and Radio Buttons</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-vs-svg-styling-checkboxes-and-radio-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-vs-svg-styling-checkboxes-and-radio-buttons/</guid>
      <description>This post is the second in the series of posts exploring techniques and examples that can be achieved using both CSS and SVG, and compares them both. In this article, we’re going to look into ways to style checkboxes and radio buttons using both CSS and SVG. You will learn how you can create animated checkboxes using SVG&#39;s line drawing capabilities. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building A Circular Navigation with CSS Clip Paths</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/building-a-circular-navigation-with-css-clip-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/building-a-circular-navigation-with-css-clip-paths/</guid>
      <description>The CSS clip-path property is one of the most underused and yet most interesting properties in CSS. It can be used in conjunction with CSS Shapes to create interesting layouts, and can be taken to the extreme to create some incredibly impressive layouts and animations like the Species in Pieces project. While exploring the creation of arbitrarily-shaped UI components using CSS and SVG, it occurred to me that the clip-path property, when combined with SVG paths, can be used to create circular menus fairly easily, especially considering the (expected) browser behaviour when handling pointer events on clipped regions as per the specification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS vs. SVG: Graphical Text Effects</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-vs-svg-graphical-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-vs-svg-graphical-text/</guid>
      <description>This post is the first in a series of posts exploring techniques and examples that can be achieved using both CSS and SVG, and compares them both. Since I am biased to SVG, this series is really intended to prove that SVG — because of its nature as both an image and a document format — is simply better than CSS when it comes to solving certain design problems on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4, Smashing Book 5</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/smashing-book-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/smashing-book-5/</guid>
      <description>The new Smashing Book is out! It’s packed with a lot of time-saving, practical techniques for crafting fast, maintainable and scalable responsive websites. I wrote a chapter in the book—Chapter 4: Mastering SVG For Responsive Web Design. Here is an overview of what that chapter covers, and why I think you should buy the book. Photo credit: Mattia Compagnucci  I always get questions from my followers about a good place to start learning SVG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Styling the Contents of SVG &amp;lt;use&amp;gt; with CSS</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/styling-svg-use-with-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/styling-svg-use-with-css/</guid>
      <description>An in-depth article on how to style the contents of the SVG &amp;lt;use&amp;gt; element and overcome some challenges it brings. We get into where the contents are cloned (the shadow DOM!), what limitations that brings up and how to work around them by taking advantage of the CSS cascade and using CSS Variables to get full control over the content while providing fallback for non-supporting browsers. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art-Directing an SVG Embedded Using &amp;lt;object&amp;gt;</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/art-directing-svg-object/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/art-directing-svg-object/</guid>
      <description>I have recently finished a front-end development project for Provata Health — a US-based health and wellness company specializing in health promotion and behavior change science. As part of their marketing website, I worked on an infographic that showcases the three major health results one can achieve by following their health program. The graphic is a perfect candidate for SVG and you’ll see why throughout this article. But even though almost all of the graphics on the site were vector (which made the entire project exciting to me), I want to focus on this particular graphic and how and why I made the development choices I made while embedding it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of SVG Animation</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/state-of-svg-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/state-of-svg-animation/</guid>
      <description>The state of SVG animation is changing. CSS, SMIL and JavaScript can be used to animate SVGs. However, SMIL is soon to be deprecated and was never supported in Internet Explorer. CSS animations on SVG elements don’t have the best browser support (yet), not to mention are quite buggy in some browsers. JavaScript is currently the best SVG animation tool. In this article, we&#39;ll go over the current and future state of SVG animation, giving you an overview of what you can and can&#39;t do, and some advice on what to choose for your specific animation needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art-Directing SVG Images With The viewBox Attribute: How-To, Notes, Tips and Why We Need A viewBox Property in CSS</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-art-direction-using-viewbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-art-direction-using-viewbox/</guid>
      <description>The SVG viewBox attribute is easily one of SVG&#39;s most powerful features. Mastering this attribute can take your SVG skills to the next level, especially considering that a couple of the main SVG spriting techniques rely on this attribute to work. Because the viewBox attribute can be used to crop and extend the SVG canvas, it can be used for art-directing SVGs—by using it to crop the SVG to the area that you want to display at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction To Graphical Effects in CSS</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-graphics/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will take a deep introduction into CSS’s graphical effects—specifically, CSS Filters and Compositing and Blending capabilities. We will go over the properties for each, their different values, and usage examples and some of the graphial effects that can be created using nothing but a few lines of CSS. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Won A Web Platform Award</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/oreilly-web-platform-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/oreilly-web-platform-award/</guid>
      <description>Today, O&amp;rsquo;Reilly&amp;rsquo;s Fluent Conf is taking place in San Francisco, California. And as part of the conference, the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Web Platform Awards were announced. Apparently, I was nominated for an award and, according to the co-chairs of the conference, I got the most amount of nominations and eventually won an award.
   O’Reilly Web Platform Awards recognize individual contributors who have demonstrated exceptional leadership, creativity, and collaboration in the development of JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and the supporting Web ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Primer To Background Positioning In CSS</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-background-positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-background-positioning/</guid>
      <description>An article in which we take a deep dive into CSS’s background positioning properties with visual explanations and examples. Did you know that the CSS background-position property accepts edge offset values? That is, you can position a background image relative to any edge—not just top and left—and specify the offset relative to that edge using a length value. In this article, we will learn all about that, and more. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Circular Navigation with SVG</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/building-a-circular-navigation-with-svg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/building-a-circular-navigation-with-svg/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I released CIRCULUS.SVG—the SVG circular menu generator. In this article I want to go over why SVG is better suited for creating this kind of UI element, and give you and overview of the SVG code for creating the menu items using SVG elements and transformations. Note that, unlike my usual tutorials, we will not be going over a detailed how-to, but only an overview of the concepts behind this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending the Color Cascade with the CSS currentColor Variable</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/currentcolor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/currentcolor/</guid>
      <description>If you use Sass or LESS, then you probably already use variables in your style sheets and know how useful they are. If you don’t use a preprocessor, then you might be curious what the fuss is all about and why variables are so popular and how they can be useful. In this article, we’re going to get an overview of why variables are useful, and get acquainted with one particular variable: currentColor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better SVG Fallback and Art Direction With The &amp;lt;picture&amp;gt; Element</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-picture/</guid>
      <description>Besides using an SVG as a background image in CSS, you can serve SVG foreground images in HTML using one of several embedding techniques, each of which has its advantages and use cases. Unless you’re in need of interactivity or external styling, &amp;lt;img&amp;gt; is the standard way for loading an SVG image, but it has one disadvantage: you currently need JavaScript to provide fallback and/or change the image source for art direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Wrote A CSS &lt;del&gt;Book&lt;/del&gt; Reference.</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/codrops-css-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/codrops-css-reference/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, we finally released a long-awaited project over at Codrops: Codrops&#39; new CSS Reference, authored by yours truly. Even though I wrote a post over at Codrops introducing the reference and its features, I want to share a little bit more about my experience writing it.
Please note that as of January 2016, I am no longer the maintainer of the Codrops CSS Reference. Thus, unlike my usual highly-technical blog posts, this is a (possibly-boring, but short!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compositing And Blending In CSS</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/compositing-and-blending-in-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/compositing-and-blending-in-css/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re a designer, then you&amp;rsquo;ve probably already come across blending effects some time or the other. Blending is one of the most frequently used effects in graphic and print design. You can add texture to text by blending it with its textured backdrop, create an illusion of merged images by blending these images together, and create a wide range of colorful effects that would not be possible without that fine level of color blending control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful SVGO[ptimization] Tools</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svgo-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svgo-tools/</guid>
      <description>One of the steps you need to do when working with SVG is optimizing the SVG code after exporting it from the editor and before embedding in on your web page. For that, several standalone optimization tools exits. The two tools I usually mention in my articles and talks are Peter Collingridge&#39;s online editor, and SVGO. In this article, I&#39;m going to introduce you to a new SVGO Tool that provides us with everything Peter&#39;s tool does, and a bit more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using The CSS :target Selector To Create JavaScript-less UI Effects</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-target-uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-target-uses/</guid>
      <description>You may or may not have used the :target selector before; and you may or may not have used it to show and hide elements without having to resort to JavaScript to handle this event for you. This article I wrote for the Adobe Dreamweaver team blog, serves as a short introduction to the :target selector, showing how you can use it to create JavaScript-less UI effects—for example, overlays, modals, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips For Optimizing SVG Delivery For The Web</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-optimization/</guid>
      <description>SVGs are a great asset in our responsive web design toolkit. But just like any other image format, there are certain steps you should take to make sure you’re delivering optimised resources that don’t have a negative impact on your page’s performance. Here are some things that you can do to make sure you’re delivering better SVGs for the web. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Overview Of SVG Sprite Creation Techniques</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/overview-of-svg-sprite-creation-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/overview-of-svg-sprite-creation-techniques/</guid>
      <description>SVG can be used as an icon system to replace icon fonts, and there are several ways to create SVG sprites. This article I wrote for this year&#39;s 24Ways will give you an overview of three of them. While we’re at it, we’re going to take a look at some of the available tools used to automate sprite creation and fallback for us. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Styling and Animating SVGs with CSS</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/styling-and-animating-svgs-with-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/styling-and-animating-svgs-with-css/</guid>
      <description>CSS can be used to style and animate scalable vector graphics, much like it is used to style and animate HTML elements. In this article I wrote for Smashing Magazine, which is a modified transcript of a talk I recently gave at CSSconf EU and From the Front, I’ll go over the prerequisites and techniques for working with CSS in SVG. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to SVG Animations (SMIL)</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/guide-svg-animations-smil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/guide-svg-animations-smil/</guid>
      <description>What the title says: a complete guide to SVG animations derived from the SMIl specification. The extensive guide features a lot of demos and goes over the animations syntax, covering almost everything you need to know to get started with SVG Animations today. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making SVGs Responsive With CSS</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/responsive-svgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/responsive-svgs/</guid>
      <description>An article on how to make embedded SVGs cross-browser responsive. We&#39;re going to cover embedding techniques, how to apply the &#34;Padding Hack&#34; and how to use inline media queries to make SVGs adaptive. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding SVG Coordinate Systems and Transformations (Part 3) — Establishing New Viewports</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/nesting-svgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/nesting-svgs/</guid>
      <description>At any point in an SVG drawing, you can establish new viewports and user coordinate systems by either nesting &amp;lt;svg&amp;gt;s or using elements such as the &amp;lt;symbol&amp;gt; element, among others. In this article we&#39;re going to have a look at how we can do that and how this can be useful for controlling SVG elements and making them more flexible (and/or fluid). This is the third and last article in a series of articles about SVG coordinate systems and transformations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding SVG Coordinate Systems and Transformations (Part 2) — The &lt;code&gt;transform&lt;/code&gt; Attribute</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-transformations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-transformations/</guid>
      <description>SVG elements can be transformed by scaling, translating, skewing, and rotating&amp;mdash;much like HTML elements can be transformed using CSS Transforms. However, there are certain inevitable differences when it comes to the coordinate systems used and affected by these transformations. In this article we&#39;ll go over the SVG transform attribute and CSS property, covering how to use it, and things you should know about SVG coordinate system transformations. This is the second article in a series I&amp;rsquo;m writing about SVG coordinate systems and transformations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding SVG Coordinate Systems and Transformations (Part 1) — The viewport, &lt;code&gt;viewBox&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;preserveAspectRatio&lt;/code&gt;</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-coordinate-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/svg-coordinate-systems/</guid>
      <description>SVG elements aren&#39;t governed by a CSS box model like HTML elements are. This makes positioning and transforming these elements trickier and may seem&amp;mdash;at first glance&amp;mdash;less intuitive. However, once you understand how SVG coordinate systems and transformations work, manipulating SVGs becomes a lot easier and makes a lot more sense. In this article we&#39;re going to go over three of the most important SVG attributes that control SVG coordinate systems: viewport, viewBox, and preserveAspectRatio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clipping in CSS and SVG — The &lt;code&gt;clip-path&lt;/code&gt; Property and &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;clipPath&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; Element</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-svg-clipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-svg-clipping/</guid>
      <description>CSS and SVG have a lot in common. A lot of the features that we have in CSS today were imported from SVG. One of these features is the Clipping operation. Both CSS and SVG allow us to &#34;clip&#34; elements into custom non-rectangular shapes. In this article we will go over the clipping techniques in both CSS and SVG, covering everything you need to know to get started.
Please note that the demos in this article may not work in your browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structuring, Grouping, and Referencing in SVG — The &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;g&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;use&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;defs&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;symbol&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; Elements</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/structuring-grouping-referencing-in-svg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/structuring-grouping-referencing-in-svg/</guid>
      <description>SVG comes with its own ways for structuring a document by means of certain SVG elements that allow us to define, group, and reference objects within the document. These elements make reusing elements easy, while maintaining clean and readable code. In this article we&#39;ll go over these elements, highlighting the difference between them and the advantages of each one.
Grouping with the &amp;lt;g&amp;gt; element The &amp;lsquo;g&amp;rsquo; in &amp;lt;g&amp;gt; stands for &amp;lsquo;group&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything You Need To Know About The CSS &lt;code&gt;will-change&lt;/code&gt; Property</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-will-change-property/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-will-change-property/</guid>
      <description>What the title says! I wrote this article for the Opera Developers&#39; blog, and it literally contains everything you need to know about the new CSS will-change property, including but not limited to: how to use it, when to use it, when not to use it, performance considerations, and more. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Forward With CSS Shapes</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/moving-forward-with-css-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/moving-forward-with-css-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Following up with the CSS Shapes 101 article, I share a list of great resources to learn more about CSS Shapes, including tutorials, examples, and developer tools. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Shapes 101</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-shapes-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-shapes-101/</guid>
      <description>In this article, you&#39;ll learn everything you need to know to get started using CSS Shapes today. We will cover all the prerequisites: establishing a coordinate system, conditions for elements to be eligible for shapes, and more, then moving on to the properties used, their values and how each one affects the shape created, with lots of visual explanations and examples. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Regions Matter</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-regions-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-regions-matter/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this article before the news came out that Google decided to pull Regions out of Blink, which, in my opinion, is a big loss for the web community. So, even though the content of the article may go in vain, I think it&amp;rsquo;s still worth sharing why I think CSS Regions mattered, and wish they weren&amp;rsquo;t ditched like that. I hope you guys like it anyway.
Disclaimer In no way is this article meant as an attack on Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating CSS Shapes with CSS Animations and Transitions</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/animating-css-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/animating-css-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Today we&#39;re going to be talking about animating CSS shapes with CSS animations. We&#39;ll be creating very basic &#34;shape-shifting&#34; layouts of sort. There are also many considerations to take when animating CSS shapes, so we&#39;ll go over all points in this article. This is the third article in a series of articles I&amp;rsquo;m writing about CSS shapes, so in this article I&amp;rsquo;m assuming you have a basic understanding of how CSS shapes are created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CSS Regions With CSS Shapes For A Better Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-regions-with-shapes-for-readability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-regions-with-shapes-for-readability/</guid>
      <description>Using CSS shapes we can flow our content in non-rectangular areas. And sometimes we want to be able to flow our content into multiple custom-shaped areas inside an element. If you&#39;ve read my previous article, you already know that this can be done with CSS Shapes, by using an image with alpha transparency with multiple shapes defined in it, and letting the browser extract the content&#39;s float areas from it. As appealing as this may sound and as creative as we can get with our shapes, flowing the text into multiple areas can easily make our content almost completely unreadable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Techniques For Creating Textured Text</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/textured-text-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/textured-text-techniques/</guid>
      <description>For too long, we&#39;ve resorted to graphics editors to create images of text that has nice effects such as creative fills or that blends with its background in a nice subtle way. We used those images as a replacement for text on our pages, which made that text unaccessible and un-selectable.. But with all the advances in web design today, we can now create textured text effects using CSS, using SVG, and using HTML5 Canvas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Techniques For Responsive Typography</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/responsive-typography-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/responsive-typography-techniques/</guid>
      <description>Text is the most important part of a website. Did you know that are several ways to make text responsive? Be it big headlines or body copy, the article will cover all those techniques, serving as an ultimate reference for making text responsive. We will cover accessibility, media queries, viewport units, and much more. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Overlay Techniques</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-overlay-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-overlay-techniques/</guid>
      <description>Overlays can sometimes be annoying, but also undoubtedly have their useful use cases. There are different approaches to creating overlays, some of them work better than others, and some of them come with gotchas that you need to be aware of, including performance implications. In HTML5, we also get a native way to create modals with less hassle and less code. In this article, we will cover all of that. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Non-Rectangular Layouts With CSS Shapes</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/css-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Today we can create all kinds of shapes with CSS using CSS transforms, but all these shapes do not affect the flow of the content inside or around them. That is, if you create a triangle or a trapezoid with CSS, for example, the shape created does not define or affect the way the text inside it flows, or the way inline text around it does.
With the introduction of CSS Shapes into the web, wrapping content in custom non-rectangular shapes, and recreating print designs and layouts on the web becomes a piece of cake!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navicon Transformicons: Animated Navigation Icons with CSS Transforms</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/navicon-transformicons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/navicon-transformicons/</guid>
      <description>The following is a collaboration post between Bennett Feely and I. After seeing Bennett&#39;s impressive animated navigation icon transformations (or &#34;Navicon Transformicons&#34;) pens on Codepen, I asked him if he would like to write a tutorial on how he did them as a guest post on my blog. He kindly approved. And as he doesn&#39;t have a lot of free time to work the article, we decided to collaborate on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draggable Metro App Showcase</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/draggable-metro-app-showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/draggable-metro-app-showcase/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;d like to share with you an interactive and touch-optimized metro app showcase concept for showcasing a metro (probably a Windows Phone) app screenshot. The screenshot will be draggable and swipable, and you&#39;ll have a couple of extra options to view how the app would look like in a mobile phone frame.
Please note that this demo works only in browsers that support the Javascript objects and APIs used. I provided a couple of polyfills but the demo will only work in browsers that these polyfills provide fallback for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building A Circular Navigation With CSS Transforms</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/circular-navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/circular-navigation/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will learn how to apply CSS transforms to fake a &#34;slice&#34; shape, creating a circular navigation using nothing but CSS (and some maths!). The article includes an interactive demo that explains visually and step by step how the technique works and the shapes are created. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S Gallery: A Responsive jQuery Gallery Plugin with CSS3 Animations</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/s-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/s-gallery/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;m going to share with you a gallery plugin I built (yeah, like the world needs another gallery plugin, right?) after having stumbled upon SONY&#39;s products gallery while I was browsing their website a while ago. Their products&#39; image gallery is a simple one, but two things grabbed my attention about the gallery: It&#39;s made with Flash when it can totally be created with HTML, CSS3 and Javascript. It has a neat feature: exiting the slideshow mode back to the grid view mode, the last image which was active in the slideshow mode &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Add/Remove Effects for List Items with CSS3 Animations</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/creative-list-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/creative-list-effects/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s not enough to bring animations and visual transitions to an interface, they should serve a purpose and goal, and this goal should be improving the user&#39;s experience.  Transitions [&amp;hellip;] provide the grease that smoothes out what happens in the interface. Without transitional effects the user can be left to wonder what just occurred.
 In today&amp;rsquo;s tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll be creating some creative animations and transitions for adding and removing items from a list, inspired by the concept from Pasquale D&amp;rsquo;Silva&amp;rsquo;s article on Medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horizontal Portfolio Layout with CSS3 Animations and jQuery</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/horizontal-portfolio-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/horizontal-portfolio-layout/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial today we&#39;re going to create a horizontal portfolio layout with cool hover effects inspired by those on Guillaume Tomasi&#39;s personal website. The website is made in Flash, so I thought it would be nice to recreate the flash hover effect of the portfolio items using CSS3 animations and transitions, and some jQuery to replicate the image pan effect on hover.
I&#39;ve also added a simple falling down effect on scroll, where the portfolio items fall down as soon as they enter the visible area of the viewport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the “Seductive Interaction Design” Book</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/lessons-from-seductive-interaction-design-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/lessons-from-seductive-interaction-design-book/</guid>
      <description>In this article today, I’m going to share with you some of the lessons I learned from one of the best books I’ve read: Seductive Interaction Design: Creating Playful, Fun, and Effective User Experiences. I believe that you should read this book yourselves to fully appreciate all the information and insight the writer has to share. I will cover only the first half of the book. I will be pasting some excerpts, because there are many things that the writer describes a lot better than I could ever do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Windows-8-like animations with CSS3 and jQuery</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/windows8-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/blog/windows8-animations/</guid>
      <description>I have recently realized that CSS3 3D transforms have been out there for quite a long time now and yet I haven&#39;t experimented with them yet. I have also been using Windows 8 for a while now, and the first thing that struck me as impressive about it was the transitions and animations built into the dashboard, so I thought it would be really cool if my first experiment with CSS 3D transforms would be to recreate those animations and effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/case-studies/cobi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/case-studies/cobi/</guid>
      <description>The COBI Connect page I built. Click on the image to visit the page.     Background   COBI’s product manager Sebastian Frommherz contacted me in January 2016 because they were looking for a front-end developer to help them build a fast page for their current marketing web site which introduces COBI’s technical features to prospect clients and users, called the &#34;COBI Connect&#34; page (screenshotted above).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/case-studies/provata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/case-studies/provata/</guid>
      <description>The Provata Health Web site homepage.         Background   In March 2015, Alex Goldberg, Provata Health CEO, got in touch with me regarding building a marketing Web site for his startup. At that time, Alex was already determined to hire me for this job because he saw me as a perfect fit for it. (&amp;lt;3)  We jumped on a Skype call for the first time a few weeks after his initial e-mail because I had been touring the world at that time, giving talks at conferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/case-studies/smashing-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/case-studies/smashing-magazine/</guid>
      <description>Please note: the screenshots shown in this case study are screenshots of the UI I built and finished early December 2016. The UI or some of its component styles [may] have changed since then, as the Smashing team [may] have made some changes to it after my work with them was finished.  Please also note that the content in the screenshots is not the real content of the magazine. I was working with static pages and most of the content I used was placeholder content and images, so that is what is shown in the screenshots as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/cobi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/cobi/</guid>
      <description>The COBI Connect page I built. Click on the image to visit the page.     Background   COBI’s product manager Sebastian Frommherz contacted me in January 2016 because they were looking for a front-end developer to help them build a fast page for their current marketing web site which introduces COBI’s technical features to prospect clients and users, called the &#34;COBI Connect&#34; page (screenshotted above).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/provata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/provata/</guid>
      <description>The Provata Health Web site homepage.         Background   In March 2015, Alex Goldberg, Provata Health CEO, got in touch with me regarding building a marketing Web site for his startup. At that time, Alex was already determined to hire me for this job because he saw me as a perfect fit for it. (&amp;lt;3)  We jumped on a Skype call for the first time a few weeks after his initial e-mail because I had been touring the world at that time, giving talks at conferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/smashing-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/smashing-magazine/</guid>
      <description>Please note: the screenshots shown in this case study are screenshots of the UI I built and finished early December 2016. The UI or some of its component styles [may] have changed since then, as the Smashing team [may] have made some changes to it after my work with them was finished.  Please also note that the content in the screenshots is not the real content of the magazine. I was working with static pages and most of the content I used was placeholder content and images, so that is what is shown in the screenshots as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About &amp; Interviews</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Photo of me taken in Sydney during Web Direction’s Respond 2016 conference.
    Named Developer of the Year in the 2015 net magazine awards, and awarded a Web Platform Award from O’Reilly, I’m a self-employed Lebanese front-end web developer, writer and speaker, focusing on HTML5, SVG, CSS and JavaScript.  I have a Bachelor’s Degree in Computer Sciences, and I work with companies across the globe, delivering websites for small and medium businesses, as well as work as an outsourcing partner to various web and design agencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press Kit</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/press-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/press-kit/</guid>
      <description>PRESS KIT  The following information is provided as a copy-and-paste resource for media publishers and conference organizers. Please feel free to use it as-is without checking with me first. If you have additional questions, you can contact me directly.     Speaker Information:  Name: Sara Soueidan   Company: N/A (Freelance)   Job Title: Front-End Web Developer   Location: Lebanon   Web Site / Blog: https://sarasoueidan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshops</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/workshops/workshops/</guid>
      <description>Want to level up your or your team’s front-end development skills, but are overwhelmed by the sheer amount of resources on different topics and don’t have enough time to read the never-ending amount of articles &amp;amp; books available? Want to get up and running fast, learning the most recent and relevant skills to get the job done? I can help.   I am currently running front-end development workshops focusing on CSS and SVG.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>