<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javascript on Sara Soueidan</title>
    <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javascript on Sara Soueidan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sarasoueidan.com/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Draggable Metro App Showcase</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/2013/08/20/draggable-metro-app-showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/2013/08/20/draggable-metro-app-showcase/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;d like to share with you an interactive and touch-optimized metro app showcase concept for showcasing a metro (probably a Windows Phone) app screenshot. The screenshot will be draggable and swipable, and you&#39;ll have a couple of extra options to view how the app would look like in a mobile phone frame.
Please note that this demo works only in browsers that support the Javascript objects and APIs used. I provided a couple of polyfills but the demo will only work in browsers that these polyfills provide fallback for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S Gallery: A Responsive jQuery Gallery Plugin with CSS3 Animations</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/2013/07/12/s-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/2013/07/12/s-gallery/</guid>
      <description>Today I&#39;m going to share with you a gallery plugin I built (yeah, like the world needs another gallery plugin, right?) after having stumbled upon SONY&#39;s products gallery while I was browsing their website a while ago. Their products&#39; image gallery is a simple one, but two things grabbed my attention about the gallery: It&#39;s made with Flash when it can totally be created with HTML, CSS3 and Javascript. It has a neat feature: exiting the slideshow mode back to the grid view mode, the last image which was active in the slideshow mode &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Add/Remove Effects for List Items with CSS3 Animations</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/2013/06/27/creative-list-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/2013/06/27/creative-list-effects/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s not enough to bring animations and visual transitions to an interface, they should serve a purpose and goal, and this goal should be improving the user&#39;s experience.  Transitions [&amp;hellip;] provide the grease that smoothes out what happens in the interface. Without transitional effects the user can be left to wonder what just occurred.
 In today&amp;rsquo;s tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll be creating some creative animations and transitions for adding and removing items from a list, inspired by the concept from Pasquale D&amp;rsquo;Silva&amp;rsquo;s article on Medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horizontal Portfolio Layout with CSS3 Animations and jQuery</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/2013/06/15/horizontal-portfolio-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/2013/06/15/horizontal-portfolio-layout/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial today we&#39;re going to create a horizontal portfolio layout with cool hover effects inspired by those on Guillaume Tomasi&#39;s personal website. The website is made in Flash, so I thought it would be nice to recreate the flash hover effect of the portfolio items using CSS3 animations and transitions, and some jQuery to replicate the image pan effect on hover.
I&#39;ve also added a simple falling down effect on scroll, where the portfolio items fall down as soon as they enter the visible area of the viewport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Windows-8-like animations with CSS3 and jQuery</title>
      <link>https://sarasoueidan.com/2013/02/11/windows8-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sarasoueidan.com/2013/02/11/windows8-animations/</guid>
      <description>I have recently realized that CSS3 3D transforms have been out there for quite a long time now and yet I haven&#39;t experimented with them yet. I have also been using Windows 8 for a while now, and the first thing that struck me as impressive about it was the transitions and animations built into the dashboard, so I thought it would be really cool if my first experiment with CSS 3D transforms would be to recreate those animations and effects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>